HABIB ULLAH

Front End Developer

CONTACT

**** 03343295024

in https://bit.ly/3TQee8e

Gulshan e Hadeed Phase-I

https://bro-habibportfolio.netlify.app

EDUCATION

2021 - 2023

ARG, GOVT, DEGREE COLLEGE

• Intermediate in Computer Science

2019 - 2021 GOVT. SCHOOL PORT QASIM

Matriculation

• Marks: 676/850

SKILLS

- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- Node.js
- React.is
- Tailwind CSS
- Next.js
- MS office
- · Effective communication

LANGUAGES

• English: Conversational

Urdu: Native Sindhi: Native

PROFILE SUMMARY

Versatile Front end development learner with expertise in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, React.js, Tailwind CSS, C, and Next.js. With 2.5 years of teaching experience in mathematics and computer science, I excel at conducting coding sessions and simplifying complex concepts, by blending them with practical coding skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GIAIC

2024 - PRESENT

SENIOR STUDENT

 Leading online sessions breaking complex topics like "ASYNC JS"," TypeScript's Strong typing features"," folder structure and behind the scene working of React.js" in simple words to students in revision sessions.

COLLEGE TECH PROJECT

2023 - 2023

TEAM LEAD

- Led the College team, created 2 projects along with my team, NO.1. smart blind stick NO.2. automated security system.
- Created both projects using Arduino (programmable circuits), programmed them using "C language".
- In which I programmed the circuits for both the projects, also created a healthy and friendly environment throughout the competition.

ISLAMIA PUBLIC SCHOOL

2021- PRESENT

MATHS & C.SC TEACHER

- Teaching mathematics to class 9 and 6 students.
- Teaching Computer science to 9 and 10 class students.

GITHUB

https://www.github.com/Habib-bhai